{
    "questions" : [
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [1~2] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "27_1_img",
            "option_1"      : "① ",
            "option_2"      : "② ",
            "option_3"      : "③ ",
            "option_4"      : "④ ",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Mr. Sumi, what are you doing here? Don't you skate anymore?\nWoman : I was taking a rest because I fell down earlier.\nMan : Is that so? Get some rest then I'll go around one more lap.",
            "correctAnswer" : "① ",
            "score"         : "3",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [1~2] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "27_2_img",
            "option_1"      : "① ",
            "option_2"      : "② ",
            "option_3"      : "③ ",
            "option_4"      : "④ ",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Do you get off work? But what kind of books are there so many? I'll listen to you.\nWoman : It's okay. Just open the door please You just need to take it to the parking lot. \nMan : Come on, give me. I'll bring you to the car",
            "correctAnswer" : "③ ",
            "score"         : "3",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "3. (3점\n여자 : 드디어 다음 주면 휴가네요. 휴가 때 무슨 계획 있어요?\n남자  : 그냥 고향에나 갔다 오려고요. 수미 씨는요?\n여자 : __________ ",
            "option_1"      : "①  동생이랑 등산 갔다 왔어요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  집에서 영화를 보는 중이에요. ",
            "option_3"      : "③  고향에 가면서 읽으려고 해요. ",
            "option_4"      : "④  친구들하고 낚시 가기로 했어요.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I'm finally on vacation next week. Do you have any plans for your vacation? \nMan: I'm just going to go to my hometown. What about Sumi?\nWoman: I decided to go fishing with my friends.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  친구들하고 낚시 가기로 했어요.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "4. (3점)\n남자 : 선영 씨, 얼굴이 안 좋아요. 무슨 일 있어요?\n여자 : 이따가 회의에서 발표할 때 실수할까 봐 긴장돼서요.\n남자 : ____________  ",
            "option_1"      : "①  실수를 해서 그런지 기분이 안 좋네요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  이제 발표도 끝났으니까 마음 놓아도 돼요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  준비를 많이 했으니까 잘할 수 있을 거예요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  몸이 그렇게 안 좋으면 오늘은 일찍 가서 쉬세요.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Sunyoung, your face is not good. What's going on.\nWoman: I'm nervous because I'm afraid I'll make a mistake when I present at the meeting later.\nMan : I've prepared a lot, so I'll be able to do well.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  준비를 많이 했으니까 잘할 수 있을 거예요.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "5. (3점)\n여자 : 다음 달부터 회사에서 중국어를 가르쳐 준다면서요?\n남자 : 네. 수업료도 무료이고 결석을 안 하면 선물까지 준대요.\n여자 :  ____________",
            "option_1"      : "①  이제는 빠지지 않도록 할게요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  그래서 저는 선물을 많이 받았어요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  무슨 일이 있어도 꼭 들어야겠네요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  재미있어서 그런지 시간이 빨리 갔어요.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I heard that the company will teach you Chinese from next month?\nMan : Yes. The tuition is free, and if you don't be absent, they'll even give you a gift.\nWoman: I must listen to it no matter what happens.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  무슨 일이 있어도 꼭 들어야겠네요.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "6. (3점)\n남자 : (전화를 받으며) 여보세요. 박준우입니다.\n여자 : 박준우 님, 안녕하세요. 여기 한국안과인데요. 오늘 두 시로 예약 하셨잖아요. 그런데 혹시 내일로 예약을 바꿔 주시면 안 될까요? 의사 선생님께 갑자기 일이 생겨서요.\n남자 : ____________",
            "option_1"      : "①  불편을 드려서 정말 죄송합니다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  선생님께 메모를 남겨 드릴까요?",
            "option_3"      : "③  예약이 많아서 오래 기다려야 됩니다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  내일은 제가 시간이 없는데 어떻게 하죠?",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Hello. This is Park Joon-woo.\nWoman : Hello, Park Jun-woo. This is Korean Ophthalmology. You made a reservation for two o'clock today. By the way, could you change the reservation to tomorrow? Something suddenly happened to the doctor.\nMan : I don't have time tomorrow, what should I do?",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  내일은 제가 시간이 없는데 어떻게 하죠?",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "7. (3점)\n여자 : (키보드 치는 소리) 아, 스트레스 쌓여서 안 되겠다. 뭐라도 좀 먹어야지.\n남자 : 그렇게 푸는 것보다는 산책이라도 하는 게 낫지 않겠어요?\n여자 : 전 이럴 땐 먹어야 돼요. 안 그러면 스트레스를 더 받거든요. ",
            "option_1"      : "①  스트레스에 좋은 음식",
            "option_2"      : "②  스트레스를 푸는 방법",
            "option_3"      : "③  스트레스를 받는 성격",
            "option_4"      : "④  스트레스가 쌓이는 이유",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Oh, I can't do it because I'm stressed. I need to eat something.\nMan : Wouldn't it be better to take a walk than to solve it like that?\nWoman : I have to eat at times like this. Otherwise, I get more stress.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  스트레스를 푸는 방법",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "8. (3점)\n여자 : 여러분은 은행의 역할이 무엇인지 아세요? 은행의 종류가 다양하기는 하지만 우리가 아는 일반 은행은 돈의 흐름을 관리한다고 할 수 있는데요. 개인이나 회사를 상대로, 돈을 맡아 주거나 빌려 주면서 여러 곳으로 돈이 돌 수있게 합니다. 이런 은행이 없다면 개인이나 회사의 경제 활동이 크게 불편해지겠죠?  ",
            "option_1"      : "①  은행이 하는 일",
            "option_2"      : "②  경제와 은행의 관계",
            "option_3"      : "③  다양한 은행의 종류",
            "option_4"      : "④  은행을 이용하는 방법",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Do you know what the role of the bank is? There are various types of banks, but it can be said that the general banks we know manage the flow of money. For individuals or companies, they can take care of or lend money and make money to various places. If you don't have a bank like this, the economic activities of individuals or companies will be very inconvenient, right?",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  은행이 하는 일",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "9. (3점)\n남자 : 여름철에 며칠 동안 계속해서 내리는 비를 장맛비라고 하는데요. 보통 6월 말이 되면 남쪽에서 올라온 따뜻한 공기와 북쪽에서 내려온 차가운 공기가 한반도 상공에서 만나게 됩니다. 이 두 공기는 힘이 비슷해서 한동안 그 자리에 있습니다. 이때 많은 비를 만들어 뿌리는데 그게 바로 장맛비죠.",
            "option_1"      : "①  장맛비의 일반적 특징",
            "option_2"      : "②  장맛비가 내리는 이유",
            "option_3"      : "③  장맛비가 내리는 지역",
            "option_4"      : "④  장맛비와 소나기의 차이",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : It's called rainy rain for a few days in the summer. Usually at the end of June, the warm air from the south and the cold air from the north meet over the Korean Peninsula. These two airs have similar strength, so they've been there for a while. At this time, I make a lot of rain and spray it, and that's the rain.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  장맛비가 내리는 이유",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "10. (3점)\n남자 : 조금 전인 오후 세 시경, 경기도 인주에서 차량 열세 대가 차례로 부딪치는 사고가 발생했습니다. 사고 신고를 받고 출동한 경찰은 사고 지역의 차량 통행을 막고 사고 처리에 최선을 다하고 있습니다. 그러나 도로가 좁아 사고 현장 정리에 어려움을 겪고 있다고 합니다. 이 지역을 지나시는 운전자분들은 참고하시기 바랍니다.",
            "option_1"      : "①  사고 처리 상황",
            "option_2"      : "②  사고 발생 원인",
            "option_3"      : "③  사고 방지 대책",
            "option_4"      : "④  사고 피해 정도",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : A little while ago, around 3 p.m., there was an accident where thirteen vehicles collided one after another in Inju, Gyeonggi-do. The police who responded to the accident report are doing their best to prevent vehicle traffic in the accident area and deal with the accident. However, it is said that the road is narrow and it is difficult to clean up the accident site. Please refer to it for drivers passing through this area.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  사고 처리 상황",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [11~13] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 4점)",
            "question"      : "11. (4점)\n여자 :  어, ‘울 엄마’네요. 그 책 정말 재미있죠? 저는 하루 만에 다 읽었어요.\n남자 :  네. 저도 사람들이 읽어 보라고 해서 읽기 시작했는데 손에서 놓을 수가 없더라고요. 사람들이 이 소설을 왜 그렇게 좋아하는지 알 거 같아요.\n여자 : 정말 재밌죠? 인기가 많아서 그런지 영화로도 만든대요.  남자 : 그래요? 벌써부터 기다려지네요. ",
            "option_1"      : "①  여자는 이 소설을 하루에 다 읽었다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  이 책은 영화를 소설로 만든 것이다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  이 책은 사람들에게 별로 인기가 없다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  남자는 여자에게 이 소설을 소개해 주었다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Oh, it's 'my mom'. That book is really interesting, isn't it? I read it all in a day.\nMan : Yes. I also started reading it because people asked me to read it, but I couldn't let it go. I think I know why people like this novel so much.\nWoman : It's really fun, isn't it? Maybe it's because it's popular, so they also make it into a movie.\nMan : Is that so? I'm already looking forward to it.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  여자는 이 소설을 하루에 다 읽었다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [11~13] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 4점)",
            "question"      : "12. (4점)\n여자 : 잠시 안내 말씀 드리겠습니다. 저희 한국마트는 개점 10주년을 맞이하여 사은 행사를 진행하고 있습니다. 물건을 오만 원 이상 사신 고객에게는 추첨을 통해 김치 냉장고, 전자레인지, 청소기 등의 선물을 드립니다. 참여를 원하시는 분은 상품을 구입할 때 받으신 응모권에 이름과 전화번호를 써서 고객 센터 앞 응모함에 넣으시면 됩니다. 여러분의 많은 참여를 바랍니다.",
            "option_1"      : "①  응모권은 고객 센터에 내면 된다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  김치 냉장고를 사면 선물을 준다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  한국마트는 문을 연 지 십 년이 되었다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  물건을 사기만 하면 응모권을 받을 수 있다. ",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I'll let you know for a moment. Hankook Mart is holding a thank-you event to celebrate the 10th anniversary of its opening. Customers who bought more than 50,000 won will receive gifts such as kimchi refrigerator, microwave oven, vacuum cleaner, etc. through a lottery. If you want to participate, you can write your name and phone number on the application ticket you received when you purchased the prize and put it in the application box in front of the customer center. We look forward to your participation.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  한국마트는 문을 연 지 십 년이 되었다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [11~13] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 4점)",
            "question"      : "13. (4점)\n남자 : 우리 몸에서 주름이 가장 많은 곳은 어디일까요? 바로 입술인데요. 입술에 주름이 많지 않았다면 노래를 부르거나 하품을 할 때 입을 크게 벌리기가 힘들었을 거라고 하네요. 그리고 입술 주름은 사람마다 무늬가 다르다고 하는데요. 이 무늬는 세월이 흘러도 변하지 않아서, 지문처럼 사람을 구별하는 데에도 이용된다고 합니다.",
            "option_1"      : "①  입술 주름의 무늬는 사람에 따라서 다르다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  입술 주름의 수로 사람을 구별할 수 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  나이가 많아지면 입술 주름의 무늬가 변한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  노래를 많이 부르는 사람은 입술에 주름이 많다. ",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Where do we have the most wrinkles in our bodies? It's lips If you didn't have a lot of wrinkles on your lips, it would have been hard to open your mouth wide when singing or yawning. And it is said that each person has a different pattern for lip wrinkles. This pattern doesn't change over the years, so it's said to be used to distinguish people like fingerprints.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  입술 주름의 무늬는 사람에 따라서 다르다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "14. (4점)\n여자 : 여보, 우리도 이번에 에어컨 한 대 사요. 요즘 할인도 많이 하니까 싸게 살 수 있을 것 같은데요.\n남자 : 요샌 날씨도 별로 안더운데요? 그리고 우리 곧 이사도 가야 하고요. 지금 사면 설치하고 옮기는 데 또 돈이 들잖아요. 이사하고 내년 여름쯤 새 집에 어울리는 걸로 삽시다.",
            "option_1"      : "①  에어컨은 할인을 할 때 사야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  이 집에 어울리는 에어컨을 사고 싶다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  에어컨의 설치 비용을 내릴 필요가 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  이사를 한 다음에 에어컨을 사는 것이 좋다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Honey, let's buy an air conditioner this time, too. There are a lot of discounts these days, so I think we can buy it cheaply.\nMan : The weather isn't very hot these days, right? And we have to move soon. If you buy it now, it costs money to install and move it. Let's move and live in a new house next summer.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  이사를 한 다음에 에어컨을 사는 것이 좋다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "15. (4점)\n여자 : 어, 민수야! 네가 웬일로 휴게실에서 드라마를 다 보고 있어? 너 텔레비전 보는 거 별로 안 좋아하잖아.\n남자 : 어. 근데 텔레비전을 너무 안 보니까 사람들하고 대화가 잘 안 통하는 거 같아서. 드라마 내용이나 개그 프로 유행어를 모르니까 다른 사람이 하는 말을 잘 못 알아듣겠더라고. 그래서 이제는 인기 많은 프로그램 정도는 보려고.",
            "option_1"      : "①  사람들이 유행어를 너무 많이 사용한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  말이 별로 없으면 사람들이 좋아하지 않는다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  유행어를 모르면 개그 프로를 이해하기 어렵다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  사람들과 대화하려면 텔레비전을 볼 필요가 있다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Oh, it's Minsu! Why are you watching all the dramas in the break room? You don't really like watching TV.\nMan : Uh. But I don't watch TV so much that I don't seem to communicate well with people. I don't know the content of the drama or the buzzwords of the gag program, so I can't understand what other people are saying. So now I'm going to watch a popular program.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  사람들과 대화하려면 텔레비전을 볼 필요가 있다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "16. (4점)\n남자  : 수미 씨, 지금 인터넷에서 정보 찾고 있는 거예요?\n여자 : 네. 인터넷만큼 정보가 많은 곳도 없잖아요. 검색도 쉽게 할 수 있고요.\n남자 : 인터넷에 정보가 많기는 하지만 사실이 아닌 정보도 정말 많대요. 중요한 내용은 인터넷에서 찾지 말고 책에서 찾으세요. 책은 그 분야의 전문가가 쓴 거니까 믿을 수 있잖아요.  ",
            "option_1"      : "①  인터넷은 정보가 많아서 편리하다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  중요한 정보는 책에서 찾는 것이 좋다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  인터넷은 빠르게 검색할 수 있어서 좋다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  책을 읽을 때는 전문가가 쓴 책을 읽어야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Sumi, are you looking for information on the internet right now?\nWoman : Yes. There's no place with as much information as the Internet. You can also search easily.\nMan: There is a lot of information on the Internet, but there is also a lot of information that is not true. Don't look for important things on the Internet, look them in books. The book was written by an expert in that field, so you can believe it.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  중요한 정보는 책에서 찾는 것이 좋다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "17. (4점)\n여자 : 요즘은 이렇게 식료품에 영양 성분이 크게 표시가 돼 있어서 참 좋은 것 같아요. 저같이 건강에 신경을 쓰는 사람들한테는 큰 도움이 된다니까요.\n남자 : 그건 그래요. 그런데 영양 성분만 이렇게 써 놓지 말고 원재료명도 좀 크게 써 놓으면 좋겠어요. 이것도 보면 뭘로 만들었는지 너무 작게 쓰여 있어서 도통 알아보기 힘들잖아요. 저같이 알레르기가 있는 사람들한테는 영양 성분보다 원재료명이 더 중요한데 말이에요.",
            "option_1"      : "①  영양 성분을 꼭 표시해 놓아야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  원재료명을 알아보기 쉽게 표시해야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  건강을 위해서 영양 성분을 확인해야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  원재료명을 영양 성분보다 크게 써 놓아야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I think it's really good that there are a lot of nutritional ingredients in groceries these days. It's a great help to people like me who care about their health.\nMan : That's right. But I don't want to write only the nutritional ingredients like this, but also write the name of the raw material a little bigger. If you look at this, it's hard to tell what it's made of because it's written too small. For people with allergies like me, the name of the raw material is more important than the nutritional ingredients.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  원재료명을 알아보기 쉽게 표시해야 한다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [18~20] 다음 대화를 듣고 남자가 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "18. (3점)\n여자 : 민수야, 너 지금 빨래하려고? 세탁기 고장 났는데.\n남자 : 그래? 이 티셔츠 내일 입어야 되는데. 그럼 손으로 빨아야 되는 거야?\n여자 : 티셔츠가 그거밖에 없는 것도 아니고. 다른 거 입으면 되지.\n남자 : 이거 내일 행사 때 꼭 입어야 되는 단체 티셔츠거든. (작게 한숨 쉬며) 빨리 세탁기 돌려 놓고 나가려고 했더니. (귀여운 척하며) 나 급한 볼일이 있어서 나가야 되는데 누나가 좀 해 주면 안 돼?\n여자 : 알았어. 그럼 이리 줘.\n남자 :  어, 역시 우리 누나밖에 없어.",
            "option_1"      : "①  티셔츠를 빤다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  세탁기를 돌린다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  볼일을 보러 간다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  다른 티셔츠를 찾는다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Minsu, are you going to do the laundry now? The washing machine is broken.\nMan : Is that so? I have to wear this T-shirt tomorrow. Then do I have to wash it with my hands?\nWoman : That's not the only T-shirt. You can wear something else.\nMan: This is a group T-shirt that you must wear at tomorrow's event. (With a small sigh) I tried to put the washing machine back quickly and go out. (Pretending to be cute) I have to go out because I have something urgent to do, can you do it for me?\nWoman : Okay. Then give it to me.\nMan: Oh, there's only my sister.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  티셔츠를 빤다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [18~20] 다음 대화를 듣고 남자가 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "19. (3점)\n남자 : 수미 너, 이번에 우리 회사에 지원한다고? 준비는 잘 돼 가?\n여자 : 나름대로 한다고는 하는데, 자기소개서 쓰는 게 처음이라서 어떻게 써야 할지 잘 모르겠어요. 그래서 이렇게 선배님을 찾아온 거예요.\n남자 : 그래, 잘 왔다. 모든 회사가 다 마찬가지겠지만 자기소개서를 쓸 때는 그 회사에서 어떤 사람을 원하는지 알아보는 게 우선인 것 같아.\n여자 : 그러면 회사 홈페이지 같은 것들을 참고하면 도움이 될까요?\n남자 : 그렇지. 그걸 참고해서 네가 우리 회사에 꼭 필요한 사람이라는 걸 보여 줘야 돼.\n여자 : 그래야겠네요. 준비하다가 궁금한 게 있으면 또 물어볼게요.  ",
            "option_1"      : "①  자기소개서를 쓴다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  지원 서류를 제출한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  지원할 회사를 알아본다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  회사 홈페이지를 살펴본다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Sumi, are you applying to our company this time? How's your preparation going?\nWoman : They say they do it in their own way, but it's my first time writing a self-introduction, so I don't know how to write it. That's why I came to you like this.\nMan : Yes, well come. It's the same for all companies, but when writing a cover letter, I think the priority is to find out what kind of person the company wants.\nWoman: Then would it be helpful to refer to things like the company's homepage?\nMan : It is. You have to refer to it and show that you are a necessary person for our company.\nWoman : I should. I'll ask you again if I have any questions while I'm preparing.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  회사 홈페이지를 살펴본다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [18~20] 다음 대화를 듣고 남자가 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "20. (3점)\n남자 : 부장님. 말씀하신 기획안요, 어느 정도 준비됐는데요. 출력해서 드릴까요?\n여자 : 이메일로 보내 주세요. 지금은 메일만 확인하고 자세한 검토 의견은 출장 가서 줘야 될 것 같아요. 출장 준비하느라고 좀 바빠서요.\n남자 : 네, 알겠습니다. 그런데 부장님, 출장 가 계신 동안 기획안 보고는 어떻게 할까요?\n여자 : 출장 가서도 연락은 주고받을 수 있으니까 이메일이나 전화로 보고해 주세요. 그런데 기획안은 보냈나요?\n남자 : 네, 지금 막 보냈습니다.  ",
            "option_1"      : "① 직원 야유회로 갈 만한 데를 찾아본다.",
            "option_2"      : "② 피자집에 전화해서 주문한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③ 직원 야유회 날짜를 직원들에게 알린다.",
            "option_4"      : "④ 직원 야유회에 모두 참석하라고 전한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Manager. It's the plan you mentioned, it's prepared to some extent. Do you want me to print it out.\nWoman : Please send me an email. For now, I think I'll just check the email and give you a detailed review opinion on a business trip. I'm a little busy preparing for a business trip.\nMan : Yes, I got it. By the way, manager, how should I report the plan while you are on a business trip?\nWoman : We can keep in touch even when we go on a business trip, so please report it by email or phone. By the way, did you send the plan?\nMan : Yes, I just sent it.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③ 직원 야유회 날짜를 직원들에게 알린다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "21. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오. \n여자 : 오늘 ‘파워인터뷰’에는 세계 각지를 여행하며 재미있는 여행기를 활발히 써 오신 김민수 선생님께서 자리해 주셨습니다. 선생님, 안녕하세요? 한국에 돌아오신 지 얼마 안 됐다고 들었는데요.\n남자 : 네, 3년 전부터 준비해 왔던 책을 출판하게 됐는데, 그것 때문에 잠깐 들어왔습니다.\n여자 : 그럼 이번에 내신 책도 여행과 관련된 내용인가요?\n남자 : 네, 여행하는게제일이니까요. 이번에낸책은지난3년간여행했던 나라들에 대한 글들을 묶은 건데요. 여기에 등장하는 나라들은 한국 사람들에게 잘 알려지지 않은 곳이에요. 그 특별한 경험들을 정리해서 책으로 낸 거죠. 앞으로도 이런 작업들을 계속할 예정입니다.",
            "option_1"      : "①  남자는 아직 앞으로의 여행 계획이 없다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  남자는 이번에 처음으로 자신의 책을 냈다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  남자는 여행하면서 특별한 경험들을 했다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  남자는 3년 전부터 준비했던 일을 곧 마칠 계획이다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : In today's 'Power Interview', Mr. Kim Min-soo, who traveled all over the world and actively wrote interesting travel stories, was there. How are you sir I heard it hasn't been long since you came back to Korea.\nMan: Yes, I've been publishing a book that I've been preparing for 3 years, and that's why I came in for a while.\nWoman: Then is the book you published this time also related to travel?\nMan: Yes, it's the first time to travel. This book is a collection of articles about the countries I've traveled to for the past three years. The countries that appear here are not well known to the Korean people. I organized those special experiences and made them into a book. We will continue to do these tasks in the future.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  남자는 여행하면서 특별한 경험들을 했다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "22. 남자는 누구인지 고르십시오.\n여자 : 오늘 ‘파워인터뷰’에는 세계 각지를 여행하며 재미있는 여행기를 활발히 써 오신 김민수 선생님께서 자리해 주셨습니다. 선생님, 안녕하세요? 한국에 돌아오신 지 얼마 안 됐다고 들었는데요.\n남자 : 네, 3년 전부터 준비해 왔던 책을 출판하게 됐는데, 그것 때문에 잠깐 들어왔습니다.\n여자 : 그럼 이번에 내신 책도 여행과 관련된 내용인가요?\n남자 : 네, 여행하는게제일이니까요. 이번에낸책은지난3년간여행했던 나라들에 대한 글들을 묶은 건데요. 여기에 등장하는 나라들은 한국 사람들에게 잘 알려지지 않은 곳이에요. 그 특별한 경험들을 정리해서 책으로 낸 거죠. 앞으로도 이런 작업들을 계속할 예정입니다.",
            "option_1"      : "①  소설가",
            "option_2"      : "②  여행가",
            "option_3"      : "③  출판사 직원",
            "option_4"      : "④  잡지사 기자",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : In today's 'Power Interview', Mr. Kim Min-soo, who traveled all over the world and actively wrote interesting travel stories, was there. How are you sir I heard it hasn't been long since you came back to Korea.\nMan: Yes, I've been publishing a book that I've been preparing for 3 years, and that's why I came in for a while.\nWoman: Then is the book you published this time also related to travel?\nMan: Yes, it's the first time to travel. This book is a collection of articles about the countries I've traveled to for the past three years. The countries that appear here are not well known to the Korean people. I organized those special experiences and made them into a book. We will continue to do these tasks in the future.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  여행가",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [23~24] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "23. 남자는 무엇을 하고 있는지 고르십시오.\n여자 :  ‘1339’ 서비스가 문을 연 지 올해로 2년째가 되었는데요. 센터장으로 계신 이진석 박사님을 모시고 이야기 나눠 보겠습니다. 박사님, 그동안 얼마나 많은 분들이 이용하셨나요?\n남자 : 작년에 약 43만 명의 시민들이 저희 서비스를 이용했습니다. 만족도도 92%로 매우 높았고요. 이제는 시민들에게 없어서는 안 될 중요한 의료 서비스로 자리 잡았다고 분석할 수 있겠습니다. 저희 센터에서는 질병 상담과 의료 기관 안내, 응급 처지 방법 등에 대한 전화 상담을 하고 있는데요. 병원 진료가 없는 명절이나 심야에 이용하시는 분들이 많습니다. 특히 응급 상황이 발생했을 때 빠르고 정확한 상담을 받을 수 있어서 큰 도움이 되었다는 시민들이 많았습니다. ",
            "option_1"      : "①  ‘1339’ 서비스의 성과를 밝히고 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  ‘1339’ 서비스의 문제점을 분석하고 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  ‘1339’ 서비스의 필요성을 주장하고 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  ‘1339’ 서비스의 개선 방안을 알려 주고 있다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : It's been 2 years since the '1339' service opened. Let's talk with Dr. Jin-seok Lee, who is the director of the center. Doctor, how many people have used it so far?\nMan : About 430,000 citizens used our service last year. Satisfaction was also very high at 92%. Now, we can analyze that it has become an indispensable and important medical service for citizens. Our center provides a video chat about disease counseling, medical institution guidance, and emergency treatment methods. There are many people who use it on holidays or late at night when there is no hospital treatment. In particular, there were many citizens who found it very helpful to be able to get a quick and accurate consultation in the event of an emergency.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  ‘1339’ 서비스의 성과를 밝히고 있다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [23~24] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "24. 1339’ 서비스를 시작한 이유를 고르십시오. ",
            "option_1"      : "①  전화로 의료 상담을 해 주기 위해서",
            "option_2"      : "②  급할 때 병원 진료를 대신 해 주기 위해서",
            "option_3"      : "③  다양한 의료 서비스의 종류를 안내해 주기 위해서",
            "option_4"      : "④  전화로 의료 기관에 대한 불만을 접수해 주기 위해서",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : It's been 2 years since the '1339' service opened. Let's talk with Dr. Jin-seok Lee, who is the director of the center. Doctor, how many people have used it so far?\nMan : About 430,000 citizens used our service last year. Satisfaction was also very high at 92%. Now, we can analyze that it has become an indispensable and important medical service for citizens. Our center provides a video chat about disease counseling, medical institution guidance, and emergency treatment methods. There are many people who use it on holidays or late at night when there is no hospital treatment. In particular, there were many citizens who found it very helpful to be able to get a quick and accurate consultation in the event of an emergency.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  전화로 의료 상담을 해 주기 위해서",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "25. 여자의 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (4점)\n여자 : 미술 감상 하면, 여기 계신 분들도 대부분 부담스럽게 느끼실 텐데요. 저는 그림의 배경을 알면 그게 그렇게 어렵지만은 않다고 말씀드리고 싶습니다. ‘아는 만큼 보인다’는 말도 있잖아요. 예전에 제가 박선우 화가의 그림을 봤을 때가 기억나네요. ‘봄의 풍경’이라는 제목이었는데 그림 전체가 까맣게 칠해져 있어서 전혀 봄 풍경처럼 느껴지지 않았어요. 왜 그렇게 그렸는지 이해할 수가 없어서 화가에 대해 알아봤는데요. 그 그림은 가족을 잃은 후에 그린 거였더라고요. 자신이 느끼는 슬픔을 그렇게 표현한 거죠. 화가에 대해 알고 나니까 그제서야 그림이 이해가 됐습니다. 여러분도 그림을 감상할 때 그 그림의 화가가 누구인지, 또 어떻게 그 그림을 그리게 되었는지 알아보세요. 그러면 그림의 의미가 더 쉽게 다가올 겁니다. ",
            "option_1"      : "①  그림을 통해서 화가의 삶을 추측하기는 어렵다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  그림을 제대로 감상하는 것은 쉬운 일이 아니다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  그림을 많이 볼수록 그림의 의미를 더 잘 알 수 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  그림이 그려진 배경을 알면 그림을 이해하기가 더 쉽다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : When it comes to art appreciation, most of the people here will feel burdened. I want to tell you that it's not that difficult if you know the background of the picture. There's a saying, 'You can see as much as you know.' I remember when I saw a painting by painter Park Seon-woo before. It was titled 'Landscape of Spring', but the whole painting was painted black, so it didn't feel like a spring landscape at all. I couldn't understand why I drew it like that, so I looked into the painter. The picture was painted after losing a family. That's how you express your sadness. After I found out about the painter, I finally understood the picture. When you appreciate a painting, find out who the artist of the painting is and how you came to draw it. Then the meaning of the picture will come more easily.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  그림이 그려진 배경을 알면 그림을 이해하기가 더 쉽다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "26. 여자가 제시한 주장의 근거로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (3점)\n여자 : 미술 감상 하면, 여기 계신 분들도 대부분 부담스럽게 느끼실 텐데요. 저는 그림의 배경을 알면 그게 그렇게 어렵지만은 않다고 말씀드리고 싶습니다. ‘아는 만큼 보인다’는 말도 있잖아요. 예전에 제가 박선우 화가의 그림을 봤을 때가 기억나네요. ‘봄의 풍경’이라는 제목이었는데 그림 전체가 까맣게 칠해져 있어서 전혀 봄 풍경처럼 느껴지지 않았어요. 왜 그렇게 그렸는지 이해할 수가 없어서 화가에 대해 알아봤는데요. 그 그림은 가족을 잃은 후에 그린 거였더라고요. 자신이 느끼는 슬픔을 그렇게 표현한 거죠. 화가에 대해 알고 나니까 그제서야 그림이 이해가 됐습니다. 여러분도 그림을 감상할 때 그 그림의 화가가 누구인지, 또 어떻게 그 그림을 그리게 되었는지 알아보세요. 그러면 그림의 의미가 더 쉽게 다가올 겁니다.",
            "option_1"      : "①  관찰 결과",
            "option_2"      : "②  자신의 경험",
            "option_3"      : "③  인터뷰 내용",
            "option_4"      : "④  실제 조사 자료",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : When it comes to art appreciation, most of the people here will feel burdened. I want to tell you that it's not that difficult if you know the background of the picture. There's a saying, 'You can see as much as you know.' I remember when I saw a painting by painter Park Seon-woo before. It was titled 'Landscape of Spring', but the whole painting was painted black, so it didn't feel like a spring landscape at all. I couldn't understand why I drew it like that, so I looked into the painter. The picture was painted after losing a family. That's how you express your sadness. After I found out about the painter, I finally understood the picture. When you appreciate a painting, find out who the artist of the painting is and how you came to draw it. Then the meaning of the picture will come more easily.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  자신의 경험",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [27~28] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "27. 여자의 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.\n남자 : 저는 식당이나 미용실 같은 가게들은, 바깥에 가격표를 붙이도록 의무화해야 한다고 생각합니다. 누구나 한두 번쯤은 가게에 들어 갔다가 값이 비싸서 그냥 나온 경험이 있을 텐데요. 가격표를 밖에 붙여 놓으면 그런 불편함은 없어질 거라고 생각합니다. 그리고 그렇게 되면 가게들끼리 손님을 끌기 위해서 가격 경쟁을 하게 될 테니까 가격이 인하되는 효과도 볼 수 있을 거고요.\n여자 : 저도 가격표가 밖에 붙어 있으면 손님들이 가게를 선택하는 데는 도움이 될 거라고 생각합니다. 물론 가격도 조금은 싸질 수 있겠죠. 하지만 그게 꼭 좋기만 할까요? 가게들끼리 가격을 낮추기 위해 경쟁하다 보면 음식이나 서비스의 질은 점점 나빠질 게 뻔합니다. 그렇다면 그건 유익한 게 아니라 오히려 피해를 주는 것이 되겠죠.",
            "option_1"      : "①  가격표를 밖에 붙이도록 의무화하기는 쉽지 않다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  요즘 가게마다 가격표를 밖에 붙여 놓아서 편리하다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  가격표가 밖에 붙으면 가격이 인하되는 효과를 볼 수 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  가격표를 밖에 붙이지 않더라도 가격 경쟁은 피할 수 없다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : I think stores like restaurants and hair salons should be mandatory to put a price tag outside. Everyone must have entered the store once or twice and just came out because it was expensive. If you put the price tag outside, I think that inconvenience will go away. And if that happens, the stores will compete for the price to attract customers, so you can see the effect of lowering the price.\nWoman : I also think that if the price tag is attached outside, it will help customers choose a store. Of course, the price can be a little cheaper. But is it just good? It is obvious that the quality of food and service will get worse as stores compete with each other to lower the price. Then it's not beneficial, but rather damaging.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  가격표가 밖에 붙으면 가격이 인하되는 효과를 볼 수 있다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [27~28] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "28. 여자의 생각이나 태도로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  구체적인 자료를 제시하며 사실을 명확하게 밝히고 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  상대방과의 의견 차이가 좁혀지지 않아서 답답해 하고 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  자신의 잘못을 인정하면서 상대방의 의견을 받아들이고 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  상대방의 의견에 일부 동의하면서 자신의 생각을 말하고 있다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : I think stores like restaurants and hair salons should be mandatory to put a price tag outside. Everyone must have entered the store once or twice and just came out because it was expensive. If you put the price tag outside, I think that inconvenience will go away. And if that happens, the stores will compete for the price to attract customers, so you can see the effect of lowering the price.\nWoman : I also think that if the price tag is attached outside, it will help customers choose a store. Of course, the price can be a little cheaper. But is it just good? It is obvious that the quality of food and service will get worse as stores compete with each other to lower the price. Then it's not beneficial, but rather damaging.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  상대방의 의견에 일부 동의하면서 자신의 생각을 말하고 있다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [29~30] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "29. 이 뉴스의 제목으로 가장 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (4점)\n남자 : 요즘 사무실 분위기를 보다 효율적으로 바꾸려는 회사들이 늘고 있다고 합니다. 어떤 모습일지 궁금한데요. 박주연 기자가 취재 했습니다.\n여자 : 광고업체인 이 회사는 개인별로 정해 놓았던 자리를 과감히 없애고 공용 공간을 늘렸습니다. 사무실 내에서 자기 자리와 자기 책상이 없어진 셈인데요. 공간도 절약하고 업무의 효율성도 높이기 위해서 라고 합니다. 직원들은 그날 맡은 업무와 개인의 취향에 따라 자리를 선택해 앉는데요. 공간을 정해 놓지 않고 자유롭게 움직이며 일하다 보니 직원들 간에 의견을 나누기도 쉽고 창의적인 사고도 가능하게 되었다고 합니다. 이같이 사무실의 환경을 바꾸려는 기업들은 앞으로도 계속 늘어날 것으로 보입니다. ",
            "option_1"      : "①  개인의 취향 살려 업무 선택해",
            "option_2"      : "②  창의적인 사고로 기업 문화 바꿔",
            "option_3"      : "③  업무 효율성 위해 개인 공간 없애",
            "option_4"      : "④  사무실 환경 바꾸니 책상 쓸모없어",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : These days, more and more companies are trying to change the office atmosphere more efficiently. I wonder what it will look like. Reporter Park Joo-yeon covered it.\nWoman : This company, an advertising company, has boldly eliminated individual positions and increased public space. Your seat and your desk are missing in the office. It is said to save space and increase work efficiency. The employees choose their seats according to their work and personal preferences. As we move and work freely without setting a space, it is easy to share opinions among employees and creative thinking has become possible. It seems that the number of companies that want to change the office environment like this will continue to grow.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  업무 효율성 위해 개인 공간 없애",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [29~30] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "30. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (3점)\n남자 : 요즘 사무실 분위기를 보다 효율적으로 바꾸려는 회사들이 늘고 있다고 합니다. 어떤 모습일지 궁금한데요. 박주연 기자가 취재 했습니다.\n여자 : 광고업체인 이 회사는 개인별로 정해 놓았던 자리를 과감히 없애고 공용 공간을 늘렸습니다. 사무실 내에서 자기 자리와 자기 책상이 없어진 셈인데요. 공간도 절약하고 업무의 효율성도 높이기 위해서 라고 합니다. 직원들은 그날 맡은 업무와 개인의 취향에 따라 자리를 선택해 앉는데요. 공간을 정해 놓지 않고 자유롭게 움직이며 일하다 보니 직원들 간에 의견을 나누기도 쉽고 창의적인 사고도 가능하게 되었다고 합니다. 이같이 사무실의 환경을 바꾸려는 기업들은 앞으로도 계속 늘어날 것으로 보입니다. ",
            "option_1"      : "①  공간 구분이 없어지면서 창의적인 사고가 가능해졌다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  직원들의 편의를 위해 공용 공간을 늘리는 회사가 많다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  직원들은 자신의 업무에 맞춰서 자유롭게 자리를 정한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  개인별 자리를 없애자 직원들끼리 의견을 교환하기가 쉬워졌다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : These days, more and more companies are trying to change the office atmosphere more efficiently. I wonder what it will look like. Reporter Park Joo-yeon covered it.\nWoman : This company, an advertising company, has boldly eliminated individual positions and increased public space. Your seat and your desk are missing in the office. It is said to save space and increase work efficiency. The employees choose their seats according to their work and personal preferences. As we move and work freely without setting a space, it is easy to share opinions among employees and creative thinking has become possible. It seems that the number of companies that want to change the office environment like this will continue to grow.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  직원들의 편의를 위해 공용 공간을 늘리는 회사가 많다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        }
    ]
}
